Coordonnées

mbmoreirab@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/maria-moreira-62442411 (LinkedIn)

Principales compétences

Private Equity
Python (Programming Language)
Mergers & Acquisitions (M&A)

Languages

Portugais (Full Professional)
Anglais (Native or Bilingual)
Français (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

CFA Level 2 candidate

MARIA MOREIRA

Desktop Specialist at Refinitiv - Deal origination on Investment Banking and Private Equity.

Lisbonne

Résumé

After finishing my studies of Business Economics and Corporate Finance in the South of France I joined an advisory boutique in Paris. My main responsibilities where originating mandates and working on the deal execution of M&A deals and Private Equity advisory (fundraising). Very quickly, thanks to my language and commercial skills, I proved a strong expertise at originating new business opportunities mostly on Southern Europe and the UK. At the same time, on the analytical side of my function, I gained expertise on doing financial analysis, business valuation, business plan creation and due diligence on clients we were mandated for. I am passionate of Maths, Statistics and Financial markets as a whole. I am currently getting prepared for the CFA level 2 exam. I moved to Portugal 3 years ago, and now at Refinitiv my main responsibility is gaining market share on the Investment Banking and Investment Management space. I am extremely confident on this region since positive growth has been seen and many opportunities arise every day.

At the current moment, I am keen to hear of any type of project in which my skills / capabilities could be challenged either on originating business opportunities but also for more analytical purposes.

Expérience

Refinitiv

Proposition Sales for Asset Management and Investment Banking janvier 2019 - Present (1 an 8 mois)

Lisbon Area, Portugal

Thomson Reuters

Client Specialist for Asset Management and Investment Banking juin 2012 - décembre 2018 (6 ans 7 mois)

Région de Paris, France

AXONIA PARTNERS

M&A / Private Equity Advisory - Associate septembre 2008 - mai 2012 (3 ans 9 mois)

Région de Paris, France

M&A and Private Equity Advisory (Private Placements)

SORBONNE FINANCE

M&A / Private Equity Advisory - Analyst mars 2007 - août 2008 (1 an 6 mois)

Région de Paris, France

M&A and Private Equity Advisory (Private Placements)

Dell

Sales Representative mars 2006 - décembre 2006 (10 mois)

Montpellier Area, France

Arval BNP Paribas Group Sales Representative septembre 2005 - février 2006 (6 mois)

Région de Paris, France

Formation

Montpellier Business School

B.Sc. in International Management (Double Degree) , Corporate Finance \cdot (2004 - 2005)

Católica Lisbon School of Business and Economics Executive Master, Fixed Income Strategies (2017 - 2017)

University of Montpellier

Master's degree , Corporate Finance and Audit · (2006 - 2007)

Universidad Del Pacifico - Ecuador Bachelor's degree, Business Administration with a major in Finance · (2001 - 2004)